A Guide to the Max Oser films FA266
Rockefeller Archive Center
Max Oser films
1928-1940
Rockefeller Archive Center
Oser, Max
FA266
6 Cubic Feet Forty five (45) individual 16mm films
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research.
Scope and Contents
45 black-and-white films shot by the Oser Family in the 1920s-1940s. The films are silent, unedited travelogues with footage from around the world. Several members of the Rockefeller family make appearences in various films, as well as footage at different Rockefeller homes.
Moving Images
- Arizona 1, 1931; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1033)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access copy available.
- Arizona 2, 1931; Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1034)
- Arizona 3, 1940; Silent, Black and white, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1054)
- Arizona and California, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1022)
- Arizona and California 2, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1028)
- Arizona and California 3, 1930; 16mm film; Silent, Black & white, 15 minutes. (Reel AV 1029)
- Arizona and New Mexico 1, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 13 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1027)
- Arizona and New Mexico 2, 1931; Silent, Black and white, 15 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1032)
- Arizona, New Mexico, and Chicago, 1931; Silent, Black and white, 15 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1031)
- California 1, 1928-1929; 16mm film; Sound, Black and white, 16 minutes (Reel AV 1021)
- California 2, 1929; Silent, Black and white, 15 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1023)
- California 3, 1929; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1024)
- California 4, 1931-1935; Silent, Black and white, 15 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1056)
- California, Chicago, and New Jersey, 1928-1929; Silent, Black and white, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1051)
- California and Florida, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1052)
- California, France, Egypt, India, Bali, China, and the Philippines, 1932-1935; Silent, Black and white, 12 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1058)
- Caribbean Islands, 1936; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1043)
- The Casements in Ormond Beach, Florida, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 13 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1053)
- The Casements, Panama Canal, South Africa, Chicago, New Orleans, and Mexico, 1935-1937; Silent, Black and white, 13 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1059)
- China, Japan, Hawaii, and Panama Canal, 1935; Silent, Black and white, 15 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1042)
- Egypt 1, 1934; Silent, Black and white, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1035)
- Egypt 2, 1934; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1036)
- Egypt 3, 1934; Silent, Black and white, 15 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1037)
- Egypt and India, 1935; Silent, Black and white, 15 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1038)
- Florida, 1929-1930; Silent, Black and white, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1025)
- Florida, Arizona, New Mexico, and New Orleans, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1026)
- French Polynesia, 1936; Silent, Black and white, 15 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1044)
- Gallup, New Mexico, 1928-1929; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes (Reel AV 1018)
- Gallup, New Mexico and Pendleton, New Mexico, 1929-1930; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 16 minutes (Reel AV 1019)
- India, 1935; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1039)
- India and Java, 1935; Silent, Black and white, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1040)
- Mexico 1, 1937; Silent, Black and white, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1048)
- Mexico 2, 1937; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1049)
- Mexico 3, 1937; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1050)
- Middle East 1, 1934-1935; Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1061)
- Middle East 2, 1934; Silent, Black and white, 15 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1062)
- Papua New Guinea, Bali, Java, 1936; Silent, Black and white, 15 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1045)
- Pendleton, New Mexico, 1930; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes (Reel AV 1020)
- San Francisco, Portland, and Seattle, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1030)
- Sri Lanka (Ceylon), South Africa, and Islands Around Africa, 1936; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1047)
- Sri Lanka (Ceylon) and Sumatra, 1936; Silent, Black and white, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1046)
- Santa Barbara, California, 1930-1931; Silent, Black and white, 15 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1055)
- Santa Barbara, Honolulu, and Chicago, 1931-1937; Silent, Black and white, 13 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1057)
- Various Cruises and Flights, 1932-1937; Silent, Black and white, 13 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1060)